Papers of Frederick Samuel Dellenbaugh, 1867-1937
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series V: Art, Architecture, Photography
  - Subseries 1: Photograhps
    - Photo albumfamily (FSD, Jr., others),friends (John Burroughs),interiors,scenes, circa 1903 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Drawings/sketches;Studio/photos, 1871-1876, 1884, later dates (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Series VI: Personal and Family Materials
  - Autobiographical/biographical notes and papers. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Photos of FSD: pp.1-18 (Box 23, File 2)
  - Photos of FSD: pp.19-39 (Box 23, File 3)
  - Correspondence with family members, 1929--1930 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with family members, 1930-- (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Clippings with references to and/or quotes by FSD (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Photos of Endridge (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Portrait photo of FSD: This is the last portrait of FSD and was the one sent to various friends after his death. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 3: Diaries
    - Diary of Walking trip from Ellenville to Arkville etc. in 1889 in company with Arthur Pomroy of N.Y.(original and photocopy) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Scattered pages of a diary (ies), 1895,1896 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - 1900 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - 1901 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - 1903 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - 1904 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - 1905 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - 1906 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 1907 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - 1908 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Entries, February 11, 1902 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Enclosures for 1903 diary (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Enclosures for 1904 diary (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Enclosures for 1906 diary (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Enclosures for 1907 diary (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Enclosures for 1908 diary (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Enclosures for 1909 diary, 1909 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Enclosures for 1910 diary, 1910 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Enclosures for 1911 diary, 1911 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Enclosures for 1913 diary, 1913 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Enclosures for 1914 diary, 1914 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Enclosures for 1915 diary, 1915 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Enclosures for 1909 diary (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Enclosures for 1910 diary (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Enclosure for 1911 diary (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Enclosure for 1913 diary (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Enclosure for 1914 diary (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Enclosure for 1915 diary (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Enclosure for 1916 diary, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Enclosure for 1917 diary, 1917 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Enclosure for 1918 diary, 1918 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Enclosure for 1919 diary, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Enclosures for 1916 diary (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Enclosures for 1917 diary (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Enclosures for 1918 diary (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Enclosures for 1919 diary (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Enclosure for 1920 diary (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Enclosure for 1921 diary (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Enclosure for 1923 diary (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Enclosure for 1924 diary (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Enclosure for 1925 diary (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Enclosure for 1926 diary (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Enclosures for 1920 diary (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Enclosures for 1921 diary (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Enclosures for 1923 diary (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Enclosures for 1924 diary (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Enclosures for 1925 diary (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Enclosures for 1926 diary (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Enclosure for 1927 diary (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Enclosure for 1928 diary (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Enclosure for 1929 diary (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Enclosure for 1930 diary (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Enclosure for 1931 diary (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Enclosure for 1932 diary (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Enclosures for 1927 diary (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Enclosures for 1928 diary (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Enclosures for 1929 diary (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Enclosures for 1930 diary (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Enclosures for 1931 diary (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Enclosures for 1932 diary (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Enclosure for 1933 diary (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Enclosure for 1934 diary (short entrie) (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Enclosure for 1934 diary (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Enclosure for 1935 diary (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Enclosures for 1933 diary (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Enclosures for 1934 diary (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Suberseries 4: Financial Records
    - Taxes:Correspondence with various taxing agencies, statements, receipts (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Taxes, estate (beginning February, 1935): Correspondences (FSD, Fr. with W.R. Garritt) (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - FSD estate, general, February-May, 1935:Letters of condolence; correspondence between FSD, Jr. and others with a personal, business, legal interest in the estate: (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Edward Eberstadt,
      Bert H. and Sidney Terwilliger,
      Raines Galleries,
      The Home Insurance Company,
      One West Sixty-seventh Street (R.R. Daigle),
      Rollins and Sons,
      Henry W. Smith,
      Wood and Lambert,
      others
    - FSD estate, general, June, 1935--:continuing correspondence between FSD R. and: (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Rains Galleries,
      P. Edwin Clark,
      Juan A. Almirall,
      Ellenville Electric Company,
      Annette M. Ham,
      Kendall T. Methot,
      Slawson and Hobbs,
      Arizona Pioneers' Historical Society,
      others; letter from FSD to FSD, Jr. about with list of disposition; inventories
    - 1 West 67th Street: rental statements correspondence between FSD and FSD, Jr. and, 1923-1934 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      Walter B. Jones,
      J.S. Kelly,
      Middlebrook and Sincerbeaun,
      Shattuck,
      Bangs and Davis,
      Mayer C. Goldman,
      miscellaneous items related to the building:
      clippings,
      list of stockholders,
      by-laws,
      etc.
    - 1 West 67th Street: rental statements correspondence between FSD and FSD, Jr. and:, 1935-1937 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      One West Sixty-seventh Street and R.R., Daigle,
      Wm. A. White and Sons
      lease (1935-1936) between estate and Esther Hellberg
    - 1 West 67th Street, estate: original lease;correspondence between FSD, Jr. and Northern Trust Company,Shattuck,Bangs and Davis, 1917 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Barnstormers: Correspondense of FSD,Jr. with Annette N. Ham, Paul Barnee (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Burial lots:Forest Lawn, Buffalo;Fantinekill Cemetery (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Harriet Otis Dellengaugh: (Box 32, Folder 1)
      Obits; correspondence relating to her estate between FSD, Jr. and: Shawnut Bank, Rank L. Holt; correspondence relating to the rose window in Chapel of the Holy Hame: FSD, with the J. and R. Lamb Studios: Charles R. Lamb, Karl Lamb; clippings, photos, etc. related to rose window
    - Harriet Otis Dellenbaugh: photos (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Frederick S. Dellenbaugh, Jr., Anne Goddard Dellenbaugh and children: clippings, photos. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Belle Dellenbaugh estate, general:, 1917-1923: (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Correspondence of FSD and FSD, Jr. with: Frank L. Holt, The fifthe Avenue Bank, Goodwin Procter, Field and Hoar, Slawson and Hobbs; various estate accounts, etc.
    - Belle Dellenbaugh estate, general, 1924: (Box 32, Folder 5)
      Correspondence of FSD and FSD Jr. with: N.Y. State Tax Department, Goodwin Procter, Field and Hoar, Slawson and Hobbs, Smyth, Haggerty, King and Corcoran, The Fifth Avenue Bank, Platt, Field and Taylor, Bulter and Baldwin; various estate accounts, etc.
    - Belle Dellenbaugh estate, general, 1925: (Box 32, Folder 6)
      Correspondence between FSD, Jr. and: Butler and Baldwin, Platt, Field and Taylor, The Fifth Avenue Bank, FSD; various estate account, etc.
    - Belle Dellenbaugh estate, Orchard Cottage: (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Correspondence between FSD and FSD, Jr. with: Pfister Brothers, W.R. Garritt, Lawerence S. Keir, The Terwilliger Agency, H.B. Rust, Raymond G. Cox, others; assessments, leases, tax receipts, etc.
    - Belle Dellenbaugh estate, Orchard Cottage: photos (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 5: Photo Albums
    - FSD, Jr.: Western trip (some of these photos taken by FSD), 1907 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - FSD, Jr.: Friends, scenes, one photo of FDS, 1913 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - W. Norton Goddard (father of Ann Goddard Dellenbaugh): family, home, friends, 1897-1899 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Annie and her father on Paris, 1897 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - W. Norton Goddard: Triton Club, 1898-1899 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Triton Club photos, 1898 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - W. Norton Goddard, family, friends, scenes, 1899 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Goddard friends, photos, 1899 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6: Cragsmoor
    - Correspondence, mostly related to the buying, selling and exchange of land,FSD with George and Catherine Bleakley, Bert H. and Alex Terwilliger, George G. Keeler, Mary D. Sherman, Raymond G. Cox, P. Edwin Clark, Helen C. Brown, Bernard Suydam, Frank L. Holt, Julia Northrup, Charles C. Curran, Juan A. Almirall, Charles Pfister, Annette M. Ham, other, 1929 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, mostly related to the buying, selling and exchange of land,DS with Julia G. Immess, Pfister Brothers, Bert H. Terwilliger, Lawrence S. Keir, P. Edwin Clark, Paul Barnee, Ellenville Construction Company, Juan A. Almirakkm Robert G Groves, Helen C. Brown W.H. Garrit, others, 1930 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Land:Maps, description deeds, conveyances, etc. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous items:notes and clippings; history by FSD; maps of area; FSD: The Herdenberghs; Blanche D. Curtis with drawings by Charles C. Currant:The Legend of Sam's Point (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous items:Report of meeting on the schoolhouse; house for Fred Schwabk telephone, power rights of way; Cragsmoor Country Club, etc. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Music, art, theatre:photos, programs, reviews; history of Barnstormers Theatre by FSD, etc. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - People:Obits, photos (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Homes, other buildings:photos (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Scenes:photos (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Newspapers,The Cragsmoor Journal, v.1 no. 1, 1904, v.11, no 1, 1913,v. 13, no.6 1916;The Mountain Echo, v.1, no.2, 1928, 1904-1928 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 7: Miscellaneous Saved Items:
    - Sub-subseries 1: Clippings, Maps, Brochures, Leaflets
      - Arizona (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Cody, Colonel William F. (Buffalo Bill) (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Colorado River (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - Colorado River, trips and explorations (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Grand Canyon (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Indians (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Juliwn, D./Robidoux, Antoine (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - 8, Miscellaneous subjects (Box 35)
      - People, mostly obits (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Pony Express and other riders (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Science (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Utah (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - The West (Box 35, File 13)
      - Zion National Park (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Other Items
      - Miscellaneous notes, sketches, etc. (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - Memberships, donations, citations, etc. (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - Odds and Ends (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Photos
      - Western and other subjects from various sources, Photos: (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Western subject from Beaman, Hillers, other sources (Box 36, Folder 2)